This is a prototype self-driving car that we've been working on.
これは私たちが製作したプロトタイプの 自動運転車です
We call it Chewbacca.
チューバッカと呼んでいます。
And all around it, we've embedded about 15 different sensors.
全体に約15個のセンサーを 埋め込みました
Let me show you a few.
少しご紹介します
This is a stereo camera.
これはステレオカメラです
The two cameras together, work just like our eyes to form a stereo image
2台のカメラが ちょうど人間の目のように機能してステレオ画像を形成し
that allows us to gather both image data, as well as distance information.
両方の画像データを収集でき 距離情報も得られます
This is a camera for the recognition of traffic signals.
これは信号機を認識 するためのカメラです
Often, traffic signals can be located on the other side of an intersection, so
信号機は交差点の 向こう側にあることも多いので
we use a special lens to give the camera sufficient range
特殊なレンズを使用して カメラに十分なレンジを与え
to detect the signal from far away.
遠くからでも信号機を検出できるようにしています
This is a radar, and it sits behind the front bumper like so.
これはレーダーです フロントバンパーの裏などにあります
Radars have in automobiles for years.
レーダーは何年も前から自動車に使われています
You can find them in systems like adaptive cruise control,
アダプティブ クルーズ コントロール ブラインド スポット ワーニング
blind spot warning, collision warning and collision avoidance.
衝突警報 衝突回避などの システムに使用されています
Even though radar is a mature technology,
レーダーは成熟した 技術ですが
it still gets improved all the time to make it even more powerful.
常に改善が続けられ よりパワフルになっています
While other sensors measure velocity by calculating the difference between
他のセンサーは2つの値の 違いを計算することによって
two readings,
速度を測定しますが
radar uses something called the Doppler effect to measure speed directly.
レーダーはドップラー効果と呼ばれるものを使用して 速度を直接測定します
The Doppler effect measures the change in frequency of the radar waves
ドップラー効果は物体が遠ざかっているか 近づいているかに基づいて
based on whether the object is moving away from you or toward you.
レーダー波の周波数の 違いを測定します
This is kind of like how a fire engine siren will sound differently
消防車のサイレンが 遠ざかるときと近づいてくるときでは
depending on whether the fire engine is moving away from you or toward you.
違って聞こえるのに 似ています
The Doppler effect is important for
ドップラー効果はセンサー フュージョン
sensor fusion because it gives us the velocity as an independent measure
にとって重要です 独立した測定パラメーターとして
parameter, and it makes the fusion algorithms converge much faster.
速度を与え それによりフュージョン アルゴリズムの収束を高速にするからです
Radar can also be used for
レーダーは環境のレーダー
localization by generating radar maps of the environment.
マップを生成することによって ローカライゼーションにも使用できます
Because radar waves bounce off hard surfaces,
レーダーは 堅い表面では反射するため
they can provide measurements to objects without direct line of flight.
直行路がなくても 物体を測定できます
Radar can see underneath other vehicles,
レーダーは他の車の下を見たり
and spot buildings and objects that would be obscured otherwise.
邪魔になる建物や物体を 見分けることができます
Of all the sensors on the car, radar is the least affected by rain or fog and
すべての車載センサーのうち レーダーは雨や霧の影響を最も受けにくく
can have a wide field of view, about 150 degrees, or
視野が広く 約150度もあり
a long range, 200 plus meters.
レンジも長く200メートル以上あります
Compared to lidars and cameras, radars have a low resolution.
ライダーやカメラに比べると レーダーは分解能が低いです
Especially in the vertical direction, the resolution is very limited.
特に垂直方向の 分解能は非常に限られています
The lower resolution also means that reflections from static objects can
分解能が低いということは 静止物体からの反射によって
cause problems.
問題が生じることを意味します
For example, manhole covers or a soda can lying on the street
たとえば マンホールのふたや 道に落ちているジュースの缶は
can have high radar reflectivity even though they are relatively small.
比較的小さいものでも レーダー反射率が高いことがあります
This is called radar clutter, and
これはレーダークラッターと呼ばれ
it's why current automotive radars usually disregard static objects.
そのため最新の車載レーダーは 通常 静止物体を無視します
Next up, let me show you a lidar.
次はライダーをお見せします